<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clustering on Kenneth Lee</title>
    <link>https://kenneth-lee-ch.github.io/tags/clustering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clustering on Kenneth Lee</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 Kenneth Lee</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://kenneth-lee-ch.github.io/tags/clustering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What2Cook</title>
      <link>https://kenneth-lee-ch.github.io/project/what2cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenneth-lee-ch.github.io/project/what2cook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We explore the potential of creating new recipes via text data. Our goal has two folds. First, we aim to classify the cuisine based on ingredients. Second, we want to predict an ingredient that is missing from a given list of ingredients and a cuisine name. The first task can be formulated as a multi-class classification problem. To convert the text into numerical signals, we can use TFIDF vectorizer, Countvectorizer, word embedding based on Word2Vec model. We are able to achieve 0.85 micro-averaged F1 scores for the multi-classification task with multilayer perceptrons and bag-of-words model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first task, we compare several well-known classification algorithms such as logistic regression, naive bayes, linear discriminant analysis, decision tree classifier, random forest, Adaboost, multi-layer perceptrons. We conduct grid search with 5-fold stratified cross-validation for hyperparameter tuning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the second task, we adopt two approaches to process the recipe text, which is the key to the recommender system. We first explore the recommended ingredients based on similarity to the given recipe using vectorizers; and then we examine the performance, in terms of the &amp;ldquo;top n accuracy&amp;rdquo; metric, of a baseline popularity model and a sophiticated collaborative filtering model under the ``text_preprocess method.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citibike System Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://kenneth-lee-ch.github.io/project/citibike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenneth-lee-ch.github.io/project/citibike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citibike is New York City’s bike share system established in 2013. It has become a vital part of the transportation network in New York City. It is available for use throughout the entire year. All the riders have access to thousands of bikes at hundreds of stations across Manhattan, Brooklyn, Queens and Jersey City. In this work, we would like to explore the characteristics of this bike share system and come up with recommendations that may improve the current program based on data analysis wtih the Citi Bike system 2019 data that is publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a New York magazine, Intelligencer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2014/03/citi-bikes-four-huge-problems.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2014/03/citi-bikes-four-huge-problems.html&lt;/a&gt;), there are some problems the citi-bike share system faced in 2014. We summarize them as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can we increase the number of customer (one-time user)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do we have any suggestion to attract more users, especially customer, during Winter?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riders complained as bikes went missing for maintenance or protection, leaving certain stations empty for days at a time, what can we do with that problem?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this work, we would like to explore the characteristics of this bike share system and try to come up with recommendations to provide potential solutions for the questions above based on data analysis wtih the Citi Bike system 2019 data that is publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
